# **CHRISTIAN JULIAN LIENDO**

EMAIL: cjl248@cornell.edu | PHONE: (646) 338 - 0622

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Medium

### **SUMMARY**

Full-Stack Software Engineer, experienced in Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and React with a dual B.A. in Information Science and Economics. I discovered web development as an undergrad but truly became passionate about it while working as a technical recruiter. Many personal projects and technical meetups later, I committed to a career change. As a recent graduate of Flatiron School's Software Engineering program, I am currently fully focused on launching my career as a fullstack web developer.

### **SKILLS**

- Technical: JavaScript (ES6), React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, Express.js, D3.js, jQuery.js, Ruby, Rails, Java, Python, Android Studio, PostgreSQL, RESTful API Development, GraphQL (Apollo Client, Ariadne), GitHub, Bash, HTML5/CSS3, Sass, Material-UI, Semantic UI, MVC, ORMs(ActiveRecord, SQLAlchemy), TDD, BDD, Discrete Structures, Natural Language Processing, Regression Analysis (STATA, MATLAB)
- Languages: English, Spanish, Italian

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Clarity - Frontend | Backend

A mindfulness hub (React, Rails API, PostgreSQL, Fullstack Auth using bcrypt and JWT)

- Integrated functional Material-UI React components and hooks to create a responsive lightweight UX/UI
- Levered 3 external APIs including the YouTube API to supply immersive, highly customizable content

## RoomFellows - Frontend | Backend

A relationship management system (React, Rails API, PostgreSQL, Fullstack Auth using bcrypt and JWT)

- Designed reusable React components and integrated Semantic UI styling with React Router for scalability
- Implemented inversion of control principles in React component hierarchy to reverse data flow, update state, and trigger
  optimistic re-rendering for an engaging user experience

# Catstagram - GitHub

Remake of Yelp and Instagram (JavaScript-ES6, JSON, AJAX, Rails API, PostgreSQL)

- Developed a RESTful Rails API and serialized JSON from a PostgreSQL database to respond to frontend Fetch API requests
- Implemented delegation to apply event bubbling and allow for dynamic DOM manipulation in response to user interaction

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Software Engineer, New York, NY

Nov 2019 - Present

- Calabria Pizza (Rails API, JavaScript, React, Material-UI): redesigned a full stack SPA with JWT-token based auth and admin
  dashboard according to client feature specifications
- PortfolioBase (Rails API, Coinbase API & WSS, JavaScript, React): a full stack web app that uses market data to calculate
  indicators such as Bollinger Bands and Fibonacci Retracement and execute market and limit orders through the Coinbase API

### **Axelon Services Corporation, New York, NY**

Feb 2018 - Jan 2019

### **Technical Recruiter**

- Successfully recruited for various technical positions such as Software Engineers (frontend, backend, fullstack, big data, microservices, mobile), DevOps Engineers, Cloud Architects, Scrum Masters and IT Security Experts
- Responsible for high-volume cold calling, screening, interviewing and coaching qualified candidates through the hiring process using the internal ATS JobDiva, and various VMSes.

### Tutors on Wheels, Astoria, NY

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

### **Private Tutoring Manager**

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017

- More than tripled the number of active private tutors from 10 to 31 including MA and PhD educated teachers through an
  aggressive hiring plan based on unique client needs
- Acquired and retained new clients across all subjects and grade levels by assigning educators to uniquely fit student needs, learning styles and goals

**Tutor (SAT, SHSAT, Regents)** 

Jan 2016 - May 2016

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School, New York, NY

Oct 2019

Software Engineering Immersive Program

# Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

May 2015

**B.A. Information Science** 

**B.A.** Economics

Relevant Coursework: Intro to Computing using Python, Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures, Data-Driven Web
Applications, Intro to Natural Language Processing, Discrete Structures, Networks II, Designing Technology for Social Impact